eventually our ad produces a result and
when that happens we will broadcast it
the broadcast of the result happens
exactly as before intimacies algorithm
except that the tag we carry for the
result is the Rob entry not the
reservation station number because we
have already freed the reservation
station so what we do is we now
broadcast the tag of Rob 6 with the
value let's say 15
just like with tomasulo's algorithm this
value and the tag are now given to the
reservation stations and they normally
captured the result based on the tag as
before this result is not broadcast to
the reservation stations and they
capture this result even if they need it
and those that need the result of this
instruction will capture the value 15
just like we did in tomasulo's algorithm
so this is not changed without the Rob
we would now also capture this result in
the register and update the right to
point to that register with the Rob we
don't want to write to the register yet
so we write to the Rob instead so this
broadcast value now goes to the Rob and
we write 15 here and mark the
instruction is done also the result of
the instruction is not going to be in
the registers so we do not update the
rat to point to the registers in fact
the rat is still pointing to the correct
place the result of the instruction is
in the Rob now so we don't do this here
after broadcasting its result the
instruction would be completed in
tomasulo's algorithm with the Rob we are
still not done with it yes we have
computed the result and mark the
computation is done but we have not
deposited this result in the registers
for that there is an additional step
called commit to commit this instruction
we must first commit all of the previous
instructions so each cycle we test
whether the next instruction at the
commit point is done in which case the
commit point can move on and commit
instruction so eventually the commit
point will reach here and now we will
test whether this instruction is done
find out that it's done and committed
the committing of the instruction
consists of actually taking this value
15 and writing it to the register that
the instruction is supposed to write to
in this case r1 so 15 will be written
here and also we need to update the rat
because it's pointing to the entry rob6
that entry will be freed after we commit
this instruction so instead of pointing
to rob6 now we can point to r1 so really
the updating of the rat for writing to
the register has moved from the
broadcast time to the commit time
because that's when we are actually
updating the registers and after
committing this instruction the commit
point will move even further so that the
next instruction to commit will be here
and that completes our reorder buffer
process or step by step for one
instruction as you can see many of the
things are happening exactly the same as
in tomasulo's algorithm some of the
things have changed like pointing the
right to the Rob and instead of the
reservation station writing to the Rob
on broadcast instead of the register
file and also we have added a step here
for committing all so we can free the
reservation station on this patch not on
broadcast and finally we need a new step
for actually committing the instruction